Carey Orr Cartoons
Carey Orr Cartoons
- Cartoons
  - 1916-1928
    - Letting papa do the home work., 1928; 1928.0086.Orr; The scene is of "America's Political household." In the background, Uncle Sam labeled "National Gov't" is washing dishes labeled "Increase duties of our National gov't." Small children labeled "Local Problems," are crying and pulling at his clothes. In the foreground is a woman labeled "Growing indolence of our local governments," who is reading a book labeled "Luxury." She smokes a cigarette and reaches for candy labeled "Waste." A small child in torn clothing labeled "local problems," is showing a torn piece of clothing to the woman. She says to the child, "Don't bother Mamma!" A piece of paper on the floor reads "Growing expenses of Local Gov't."of preliminary sketch for cartoon 1928.0084.Orr on recto. Preliminary sketch for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1928, by The Chicago Tribune."3 Cols am" written on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 18)
    - The little boy who almost decided to run away from home., 1928; 1928.0087.Orr; A boy labeled "Solid South" is coming out of a building from a door labeled "Wet Democratic party." It is night-time and the boy is frightened by an elephant labeled "Republican Bogeyman" who is climbing over the fence to the back yard. The boy drops his bag labeled "Dry sentiment."of preliminary sketch on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1928, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am Sunday" written on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 18)
    - A little hard o' hearin'., 1928; 1928.0088.Orr; Cartoon in three panels: 1. The scene is of an "Employment dep't" where"Frank Smith" is handing a piece of paper that reads "First appointment to Senate Seat" to a man labeled "Senate"Senate" says, "I don't want you!" 2. Smith says, "What was that you said?" Senate now has a megaphone labeled "Second refusal of Senate to seat Smith" and is yelling, "I don't want you." 3. Smith holds an ear trumpet labeled "Reappointment of Smith to Senate seat" to his ear and says, "How's that?" Senate is wiping the perspiration from his forehead."sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1928, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 18)
    - Look out, Herb! They're layin' for you.", 1928; 1928.0089.Orr; Hoover" is coming through a gate of a fence. On the other side are two men with ropes. The man to the left is labeled "Bootleggers" and the man to the right is labeled "Bone drys" with a rope labeled "Dry Domination" that is set on the ground as a trap."overlay: Copyright, 1928, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am." on recto bottom edge. " (Oversize 18)
    - Looking at us from abroad., 1928; 1928.0090.Orr; A man labeled "Europe" is looking across the ocean to the U.S. he is in tattered clothing and says "I wish I was hard up like Uncle Sam." Uncle Sam is standing with bags of money behind him. Men are yelling at him with a sign that reads: Democratic orators viewing with alarm the signs of hard times they see in America."sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1928, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge. Stamp on verso: Received 1928 Oct 12 PM 5 38 ..." (Oversize 18)
    - The lookout.", 1928; 1928.0091.Orr; A large man with money stuffed in his pockets is labeled "Political Friends of organized crime" and is standing in a doorway labeled "Protected crime." Inside the building are two criminals. A "Chicago Policeman" carries an order that reads: Order to drive the crooks out of Chicago! Chief of Police." The man in the doorways says to the officer, "Try and do it!"sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1928, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 18)
    - Losing some of his affection for his pet., 1928; 1928.0092.Orr; A bee hive in the back ground is labeled "Aroused public" and has been disturbed. Bees are swarming chasing a dog labeled "Crime." The dog is chasing a man labeled "Chicago politics" who says, "Keep away from me!"on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1928, by The Chicago Tribune." 3 cols am. Monday." written on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 18)
    - The lullaby that soothes one arouses the other., 1928; 1928.0093.Orr; In the "International Nursery,"J.B" has a lullaby that reads "Rule, Britannia, Rule!" A baby is crying in a cradle labeled "British fear of losing command of the seas." Next to this cradle is another cradle labeled "American uneasiness over England's Naval supremacy." The baby inside is listening to Uncle Sam sing "O-O, Columbia, The gem of the o -o-ocean!" He holds music that reads, "U.S. Naval program."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1928, by The Chicago Tribune." 3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 18)
  - 1929-1962, Click here for a detailed inventory for these years.
    - 1928, M-W, 89 items (Oversize 19)
    - 1929, A-N, 98 items (Oversize 20)
    - 1929, O-Y; 1930, A -E, 98 items (Oversize 21)
    - 1930, F-Y, 108 items (Oversize 22)
    - 1931, A-R, 123 items (Oversize 23)
    - 1931, S-Y; 1932, A-P, 149 items (Oversize 24)
    - 1932, R-W; 1933 Jan-Oct, 40 items from 1932 (Oversize 25)
    - 1933 Nov-1934 Dec; 1933 undated (Oversize 26)
    - 1934 (Oversize 27)
    - 1935 Jan-Dec; 1935 undated (Oversize 28)
    - 1936 (Oversize 29)
    - 1937 (Oversize 30)
    - 1937 (Oversize 31)
    - 1937 (Oversize 32)
    - 1938 Jan-Jul (Oversize 33)
    - 1938 Aug-Dec; 1938 undated (Oversize 33A)
    - 1939 Jan-Jun (Oversize 34)
    - 1939 Aug-Dec; 1939 undated (Oversize 34A)
    - 1940 Feb-Jun (Oversize 35)
    - 1940 Jul-Dec; 1940 undated (Oversize 35A)
    - 1941 Jan-May (Oversize 36)
    - 1941 Jun-Dec (Oversize 36A)
    - 1941 Dec; 1941 undated (Oversize 37)
    - 1942 Jan-Jun (Oversize 37)
    - 1942 Jul-Dec (Oversize 38)
    - 1943 Jan-Dec; 1943 undated (Oversize 38A)
    - 1944 (Oversize 39)
    - 1946 Jan-Dec; 1946 undated (Oversize 40)
    - 1947 Jan-Jun (Oversize 40)
    - 1947 Jul-Dec; 1947 undated (Oversize 41)
    - 1948 Jan-Jun (Oversize 42)
    - 1948 Jul-Dec (Oversize 42A)
    - 1949 Jan-Jul (Oversize 43)
    - 1949 Aug-Dec (Oversize 43A)
    - 1950 Jan-Jul (Oversize 44)
    - 1950 Aug-Dec (Oversize 44A)
    - 1951 Jan-Jul (Oversize 45)
    - 1951 Aug-Dec (Oversize 45A)
    - 1952 Jan-May (Oversize 46)
    - 1952 Jun-Dec (Oversize 46A)
    - 1953 (Oversize 47)
    - 1954 Jan-Jun (Oversize 48)
    - 1954 Jul-Dec (Oversize 48A)
    - 1955 Jan-Oct (Oversize 49)
    - 1955 Nov-Dec (Oversize 50)
    - 1956 Jan-Jun (Oversize 50)
    - 1956 Jul-Dec; 1956 undated (Oversize 51)
    - 1957 Jan-Apr (Oversize 51)
    - 1957 May-Dec (Oversize 52)
    - 1958 (Oversize 53)
    - 1959 (Oversize 54)
    - 1960 (Oversize 55)
    - 1961 (Oversize 56)
    - 1962 (Oversize 57)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1943-1944, 1946 (Oversize 58)
  - 1947-1948 (Oversize 59)
  - 1949-1951 (Oversize 60)
  - 1952-1953 (Oversize 61)
  - 1954-1956 (Oversize 62)
  - 1957-1962 (Oversize 63)